<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator>
  
  
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2025-03-05T10:31:09-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/</id>

  
    <title type="html">Majestic Twelve’s Blog</title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Hello! Welcome to my blog! Where I write about myself and the things I enjoy! Which are books, computers, and productivity! Thanks for visiting!</subtitle>
  

  

  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">E-Waste: How Corporations Take Control and Deceive The Public</title>
      
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/05/Research-Paper-Blog-Edition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="E-Waste: How Corporations Take Control and Deceive The Public" />
      
      <published>2025-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2025-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/05/Research-Paper-Blog-Edition</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/05/Research-Paper-Blog-Edition/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“E-Waste: How Corporations Take Control and Deceive The Public”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic Waste or E-Waste is a type of waste that mainly includes
unwanted electronics like phones and computers to household items. They
are broken or working devices that are unwanted that are being thrown
into the trash to be discarded into the landfill if they are not being
sold second hand. Electronic Waste has a lot of hazardous materials
including lead, mercury, and chromium which are carcinogenic that can
cause cancer in the human body if the electronic waste is burned. There
must be an understanding of how electronic waste became such a big issue
in society and the environment. Electronic waste poses a significant
threat to human health, and the environment due to planned obsolescence,
greenwashing and unsustainable consumer spending habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planned Obsolescence is where the lifespan of product has been
intentionally made to fail over a set period. Major phone manufacturers
shorten the lifespans of their batteries because it makes consumers
spend more money on a replacement even if the rest of their device is
working properly. For example, Google has been in the news recently
because they have intentionally shortened the lifespan of their own
Google Pixel 4a smartphone through a February 2025 software update.
Google put it out on their own blog saying, &quot; For some devices, the
software update reduces available battery capacity and impacts charging
performance.”
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/pixelphone/answer/15701861&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;) but
without telling the public the reasons why. That intentionally handicaps
the battery life on certain Pixel 4a devices. Some users were so
disgruntled that they filed an FCC complaint about this issue.
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/pixelphone/thread/317228576/pixel-4a-battery-performance-program?hl=en&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;)
“The update could mean “reduced charging performance” or change how the
phone shows battery capacity.”
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/7/24338566/google-pixel-4a-battery-stability-replacement-reduced-capacity&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;)
This is one of the reasons why planned obsolescence is so dangerous
because it can do to the environment. Nudging people into upgrading
their phones every so often. Additionally, Windows 11 from Microsoft set
a hardware limitation cause of a high system requirement. Forcing users
to upgrade their computers or deal with Windows 10 without support in
October of 2025. We will see an uptick of e-waste because Windows 11
higher system requirements. Canalys is a market analysis firm that said
that the “Termination of Windows 10 support could prevent hundreds of
millions of devices from getting second lives. These computers would put
into landfills”
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canalys.com/insights/end-of-windows-10-support-could-turn-240-million-pcs-into-e-waste&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;)
Planned Obsolescence is where companies knowingly break the functionality of their devices so they can make a little bit more extra money while not caring about the evironmental effects onto the planet and as people as a whole. So how do these companies try to make themselves look good?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greenwashing is a term that is used to describe the act of a corporation
where they try to conceal and obfuscate their environmental impact.
Major phone manufacturers use schemes like carbon offsets. Companies use
carbon offset schemes where a piece of tradable assets or certificates
that are linked to lower carbon emissions into the atmosphere. for
example, Apple will buy a piece of this tradable asset and use it to
“offset” their carbon emissions, so it looks good on their balance sheet
like investors on environmental scale.
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://climate.mit.edu/explainers/carbon-offsets&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;) Apple has
been using carbon offsets and have been accused of Greenwashing by The
European Consumer Protection group and claims that Apple is not being
environmentally friendly and carbon neutral. In September of 2023, this
is a big problem because they can use this to push their environmental
image further while shoving the actual practices under the rug. The
European Union is continuing its efforts to stop misleading consumers
about their advertising messages about how ecofriendly a product is.
Apple marketed the Apple Watch as “the first-ever carbon neutral
products”. Monique Goyens, the Director-general of BEUC (Bureau Européen
des Unions de Consommateurs.) has said that “Carbon neutral claims are
scientifically inaccurate and mislead consumers,” continued with “The
BEUC said that by 2026 it would ban “neutrality” claims that are based
on the purchase of carbon credits.”
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/Sfak0&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;). The European Union is trying to
ban uses of green marketing terms like “environmentally friendly”,
“natural”. The use of carbon offset schemes in conjunction with
misleading advertisements can have an impact on E-Waste. On the other
hand, product cycles cause more E-Waste because they already mined the
materials to make the product have and shifting their carbon emissions
to somewhere else. When it comes to Electronic Waste and how people
should continue using what they possess in their own hands and how it
impacts others and society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People&apos;s spending habits in relation to E-Waste are what a lot of
people are at the forefront of their minds and how they think about what
they own currently. The Canadian government has made a survey on how
people repair or replace their old phones and computers, Gordon Dewis
analyses that people. “Since 2011, the proportion of households that had
an unwanted cell phone that reported doing this increased from 8% to
11%.” It demonstrates that people are holding onto their devices because
of spending more money on goods that Canadians do not need. Gordon
continues this pattern of findings in computers in the paper that
Canadians are holding onto their computers than their phones. “The trend
of the rate at which households have reported having unwanted computers
to dispose of is negative.” The inclusion of computers in this study
shows that people hold onto their computers longer than their smartphone
because they become more useful as technology progresses.
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/pub/16-002-x/2022001/article/00001-eng.htm&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;)
In India there was a study of 1039 people that responded with a similar
outlook as Canadians. Indians provided their answers and explanations
about keeping their mobile devices for longer, by saying that: “Over 42%
of the respondents said that they purchase or replace a mobile phone
when the older one becomes non-functional, so people would buy a new
phone if it was not functioning.” Indians prefer to hold onto their
phones longer their Canadian counterparts. The study also finds that
people from India are not as environmentally aware as Canadians because
of the problem of how electronic waste is handled. “Environmental
awareness in India is still in its infancy where most consumers are not
conscious of environmentally responsible behaviors”.
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s40974-022-00242-9#Sec9&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;)
In the end, electronic waste is inherently dangerous to human health,
there should be programs in place to take care of the overburden of
hazardous materials. For example, the USEPA United States Environmental
Protection Agency has an initiative for cleaning up e-waste in the
Carribean.
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/international-cooperation/cleaning-electronic-waste-e-waste&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take into consideration what tech companies are doing when they are
committing planned obsolescence with artificially their own products,
greenwashing that companies use to obfuscate their emissions, then
people&apos;s spending habits on how others deal with spending money on new
electronics and how people retire older electronics. This should be
worrying to everyone who cares about the environment because electronic
waste impacts everyone, because of the carcinogenic effects on the human
body, including people who live in the developing countries, like India,
China, and many other countries in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, E-Waste poses an immense threat to human health and the
environment as a whole because of the harmful practices that companies
lean towards profit over conserving the environment. People could
consider the other possibilities of keeping our devices for longer
instead of thinking of replacing our phones and computers, whilst not
giving into planned obsolescence, greenwashing unneeded spending.
However, there are solutions that can help mitigate these problems,
including the promotion of repair culture to show that hardware hacking
is a way to remove hardware restrictions, adopting eco-friendly
manufacturing and holding people for their environmental impacts. This
can help offset carcinogenic electronic waste and help make sure that
the developing world does not end up in a broken world...&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Majestic Twelve</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="Articles" />
      
        <category term="Research" />
      
        <category term="E-Waste" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">“E-Waste: How Corporations Take Control and Deceive The Public”</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Jouranling and What it has taught about myself. Part 1</title>
      
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/15/journaling-writing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jouranling and What it has taught about myself. Part 1" />
      
      <published>2025-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2025-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/15/journaling-writing</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/15/journaling-writing/">&lt;p&gt;Journaling brings prespectives on what we are doing and how we reflect from the world onto our sheet of paper or in our text documents on the computer. (using Vim, Nano, or Emacs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should not detour you whatsoever because of someone wrote “dear diary”, and it should not put you off. A lot of people kept journals including very well known Presidents of the United States for example, George Washington, Harry S. Truman and many others. So if you are a man and reading this, it is all good to keep one for yourself. Furthermore, it brings more to the table than we realise while writing. It is an  unflitered apporach to to ouselves and it is very unique about ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding this, this is how we are going to deal with our problems, for example, it could be about your job, people, or life in general. Using the problems that we are surrounded with is tiredsome and we just want to sit down and reflect and how we could deal with all these situations in our head. Moreover, I will write about how it works for me and how you should try it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big hurdles that I first got over with when I first started to write, is when I found it to be a good exercise on what is on your mind so you can let it out and live on the page. So, when I did this every night before I went to bed, or started to write how my day should be doing (according to plan), I felt like something came off my shoulders and it was not apart of myself anymore. It was a wonderful feeling like the world felt a lot lighter than it once was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who would like world where it just could operate by itself without our minds thinking about everything?I would take this every day of the week if I just could write one day in slience without the phone rining or people bothering us. (I will talk about this in a future post). People should take a chance and sit in slience with a pen in their hand and write about whats going on.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next part why journaling and writing is great, subscribe to my RSS feed to see what comes out in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Majestic Twelve</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="posts" />
      
        <category term="journaling" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Journaling brings prespectives on what we are doing and how we reflect from the world onto our sheet of paper or in our text documents on the computer. (using Vim, Nano, or Emacs).</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">New Years and Future Updates</title>
      
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/26/new-year-updates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Years and Future Updates" />
      
      <published>2024-12-26T14:14:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2024-12-26T14:14:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/26/new-year-updates</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/26/new-year-updates/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-has-been-a-while&quot;&gt;It has been a while…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made this blog for me to write about my thoughts, but I havent commited anything because of my disipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I am going to use this to write about about my thoughts on productivity, on how I write and trying to get work done using logseq, obsidian and other types of programs so I can focus on my studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I will be trying to commit at least one good blog post a week so I can think about the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want from my future is just wanting some happiness so I can focus on reading my books, and taking care of myself through self improvement.
For example, reading every night, keeping my phones (Yes I have many phones) out of the bedroom, and just trying to keep it together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The courses that I would like to take are some cyber security exams so I can get certified so I can find some stability in a good work environment, whatever that means. but here I am…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I will try to keep in progress in here so I can show what I have to offer.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Majestic Twelve</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="new-years" />
      
        <category term="updates" />
      
        <category term="obsidian" />
      
        <category term="logseq" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">It has been a while…</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Title</title>
      
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/06/new-file/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Title" />
      
      <published>2024-03-06T22:43:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2024-03-06T22:43:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/06/new-file</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/06/new-file/">&lt;p&gt;Yes, This is a test post. thanks for reading…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just another thing, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github pages&lt;/a&gt; site is outdated and needs work…&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Majestic Twelve</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="jekyll" />
      
        <category term="update" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Yes, This is a test post. thanks for reading…</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
</feed>
