<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator>
  
  
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2025-03-04T22:36:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/</id>

  
    <title type="html">Majestic Twelve’s Blog</title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Hello! Welcome to my blog! Where I write about myself and the things I enjoy! Which are books, computers, and productivity! Thanks for visiting!</subtitle>
  

  

  
  
  
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Jouranling and What it has taught about myself. Part 1</title>
      
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/15/journaling-writing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jouranling and What it has taught about myself. Part 1" />
      
      <published>2025-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2025-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/15/journaling-writing</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/15/journaling-writing/">&lt;p&gt;Journaling brings prespectives on what we are doing and how we reflect from the world onto our sheet of paper or in our text documents on the computer. (using Vim, Nano, or Emacs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should not detour you whatsoever because of someone wrote “dear diary”, and it should not put you off. A lot of people kept journals including very well known Presidents of the United States for example, George Washington, Harry S. Truman and many others. So if you are a man and reading this, it is all good to keep one for yourself. Furthermore, it brings more to the table than we realise while writing. It is an  unflitered apporach to to ouselves and it is very unique about ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding this, this is how we are going to deal with our problems, for example, it could be about your job, people, or life in general. Using the problems that we are surrounded with is tiredsome and we just want to sit down and reflect and how we could deal with all these situations in our head. Moreover, I will write about how it works for me and how you should try it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big hurdles that I first got over with when I first started to write, is when I found it to be a good exercise on what is on your mind so you can let it out and live on the page. So, when I did this every night before I went to bed, or started to write how my day should be doing (according to plan), I felt like something came off my shoulders and it was not apart of myself anymore. It was a wonderful feeling like the world felt a lot lighter than it once was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who would like world where it just could operate by itself without our minds thinking about everything?I would take this every day of the week if I just could write one day in slience without the phone rining or people bothering us. (I will talk about this in a future post). People should take a chance and sit in slience with a pen in their hand and write about whats going on.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next part why journaling and writing is great, subscribe to my RSS feed to see what comes out in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Majestic Twelve</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="posts" />
      
        <category term="journaling" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Journaling brings prespectives on what we are doing and how we reflect from the world onto our sheet of paper or in our text documents on the computer. (using Vim, Nano, or Emacs).</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">New Years and Future Updates</title>
      
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/26/new-year-updates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Years and Future Updates" />
      
      <published>2024-12-26T14:14:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2024-12-26T14:14:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2024/12/26/new-year-updates</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/12/26/new-year-updates/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-has-been-a-while&quot;&gt;It has been a while…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have made this blog for me to write about my thoughts, but I havent commited anything because of my disipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I am going to use this to write about about my thoughts on productivity, on how I write and trying to get work done using logseq, obsidian and other types of programs so I can focus on my studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I will be trying to commit at least one good blog post a week so I can think about the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want from my future is just wanting some happiness so I can focus on reading my books, and taking care of myself through self improvement.
For example, reading every night, keeping my phones (Yes I have many phones) out of the bedroom, and just trying to keep it together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The courses that I would like to take are some cyber security exams so I can get certified so I can find some stability in a good work environment, whatever that means. but here I am…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I will try to keep in progress in here so I can show what I have to offer.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Majestic Twelve</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="new-years" />
      
        <category term="updates" />
      
        <category term="obsidian" />
      
        <category term="logseq" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">It has been a while…</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Title</title>
      
      
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/06/new-file/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Title" />
      
      <published>2024-03-06T22:43:00-05:00</published>
      <updated>2024-03-06T22:43:00-05:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/2024/03/06/new-file</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/03/06/new-file/">&lt;p&gt;Yes, This is a test post. thanks for reading…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just another thing, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github pages&lt;/a&gt; site is outdated and needs work…&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Majestic Twelve</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      
        <category term="jekyll" />
      
        <category term="update" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Yes, This is a test post. thanks for reading…</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
</feed>
